<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dirt &amp; Sky</title>
    <link>https://melinanina.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dirt &amp; Sky</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Melina Mattos</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 14:00:09 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://melinanina.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Baja California, Mexico</title>
      <link>https://melinanina.github.io/portfolio/baja_california_20150208/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 14:00:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melinanina.github.io/portfolio/baja_california_20150208/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vityugov.com/post/bahia-de-los-angeles/&#34;&gt;Gene&lt;/a&gt; and I decided to drive down highway 1 from northern California to the middle of Baja California in early January, and in 8 days, we covered about 2000 miles (3200 kilometers). As we traveled further south from the border, the size of and proximity between towns both decreased, and gas stations, ATMs, and general amenities become few and far between. Highway 1 does not offer much in terms of tourist attractions, but the landscape offsets any disappointments and is absolutely stunning: red soil, blue sky, dark green cacti sprinkled across the terrain with the occasional grey rocky mountains obscuring distant views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our destination was a small, quiet fisherman village called Bahía de los Ángeles on the eastern side of Baja California. The bay is surrounded by islands, which makes it seem more like a lake than part of a sea. The location is great for kayaking, but due to the strong day winds, we were prevented from going out onto the water. Therefore, we enjoyed the wildlife from the shore, and we saw plenty of dolphins, sea lions, and marine birds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way home to California, we visited the Cataviña cave paintings, which are a short walk off highway 1. The paintings are interesting, but the views of the landscape really make the detour worthwhile. La Bufadora in Ensenada was underwhelming, and, thankfully, we missed the hordes of tourists and pestersome vendors by arriving before 8 am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The map below highlights our route and places to visit, dine, and stay. As a note for other tourists headed across the border, the location to pick-up the tourist visa in Mexico is in the &amp;ldquo;to declare&amp;rdquo; office as soon as crossing the border (on the right); there are few signs so ask around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/d/embed?mid=zElkIPCwp184.kvixKYZpV-7E&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;480&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posted 8 February 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aerobatic Experience</title>
      <link>https://melinanina.github.io/portfolio/aerobatic_experience_20130128/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 09:48:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melinanina.github.io/portfolio/aerobatic_experience_20130128/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first arrived, the instructor fitted me in a jumper and explained the basics of my parachute. If I wasn&amp;rsquo;t already nervous, his causal instructions of, &amp;ldquo;Oh, it’s easy. Just climb out of the plane and throw yourself over&amp;rdquo; left me wondering, What the heck am I doing here?! I guess my nervous laugh showed my fear because as we discussed the lesson plan, he limited my instruction to the basics (&amp;ldquo;The advanced maneuvers come later with time.&amp;rdquo;)
The plane, an Extra 300L, is a super lightweight aerobatic plane (1500 lbs / 680 kg with a 300 horsepower engine), and takeoff was nearly instant. Once up in the air, he allowed me fly around, and I was amazed how sensitive the controls are. Light touches move the plane left, right, up, and down. About 7 minutes into the flight, I experienced audio loss in my headset, and there is &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=7m20s&#34;&gt;a few minutes of embarrassing footage of me spacing out and the instructor talking to himself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I fixed the issue, we worked our way up to a cruising altitude of 4000 feet. He guided me through some of the basic maneuvers (&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=15m00s&#34;&gt;aileron roll and loop&lt;/a&gt;), and then I repeated on my own. Easy! Perhaps because I ride aggressive roller coasters frequently, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel any &amp;ldquo;butterflies&amp;rdquo; in my stomach although that didn’t save me from experiencing four times the force of gravity on the loop. I find my face all too hilarious at the bottom!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the instructor saw that &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=20m&#34;&gt;I was enjoying myself maybe too much&lt;/a&gt;, he kicked it up a notch and did more intense maneuvers. I was surprised how easy it is to get disoriented since the best point of reference, the horizon, is not always visible and the angle of flight to the sky or ground is not always apparent. &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=20m30s&#34;&gt;The Lomcevak made me dizzy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=27m15s&#34;&gt;the last trick, the tail spin, made me queasy&lt;/a&gt;. No matter, by then, it was time to land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aerobatic flights don&amp;rsquo;t last too long because the maneuvers are extremely physically and mentally tiring; I felt like I had backpacked all weekend while working through an intense math theory exam. My exhaustion and adrenaline crash hit me hard around the second hour of my drive home, and only the heaviest of 70&amp;rsquo;s and 80&amp;rsquo;s metal kept me going. The queasy feeling also settled deep in my stomach and didn’t pass until a few hours later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course as soon as I arrived home, I had to watch my video and laugh through my &amp;ldquo;Awesome!&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Woo!&amp;rdquo; remarks. Watching the video intensified the queasiness in my stomach although I had done these tricks hours earlier with no issue! Overall, though, the experience was fantastic and would highly recommend it to adventurous and interested parties. I will definitely go back! I guess I&amp;rsquo;m twisted as my instructor would say! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;List of maneuvers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=12m30s&#34;&gt;Aileron roll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=15m&#34;&gt;Loop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=16m50s&#34;&gt;Half Cuban Eight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=17m20s&#34;&gt;Immelmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=18m30s&#34;&gt;Inverted Flying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=19m20s&#34;&gt;Hammerhead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=20m30s&#34;&gt;Lomcevak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=22m&#34;&gt;Flat spin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=23m50s&#34;&gt;Chinese Loop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=25m20s&#34;&gt;Double aileron roll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=27m15s&#34;&gt;Tailspin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posted 28 January 2013&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>