<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dirt &amp; Sky</title>
    <link>https://melinanina.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dirt &amp; Sky</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://melinanina.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Skyline-to-the-Sea in one day</title>
      <link>https://melinanina.github.io/2016/09/skyline-to-the-sea-in-one-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melinanina.github.io/2016/09/skyline-to-the-sea-in-one-day/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-premise&#34;&gt;The premise&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every once in awhile, I have these crazy ideas that I just can&amp;rsquo;t shake. &lt;a href=&#34;http://vityugov.com/&#34;&gt;Gene&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; company was running a monthly steps competition, and in order to put Gene in the lead, I suggested we do a very long day hike. After some discussion, we agreed to do the Skyline-to-the-Sea and so I started to put the plan in motion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-plan&#34;&gt;The plan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This trip required a bit more planning than your average hike. I had to manage our time, ensure we had transportation there and back (it&amp;rsquo;s a point-to-point hike and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to mess with two cars), and the right supplies and food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;time-management&#34;&gt;Time management&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I planned that we would hike about 2 miles per hour and therefore determined the following mile markers to ensure that we would stay on track throughout the day:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;6 am: mile 0 - Castle Rock headquarters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 am: mile 2 - Castle Rock Trail camp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9 am: mile 6 - Saratoga Toll road&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11 am: mile 10 - Waterman Gap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pm: mile 14 - China Grade crossing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 pm: mile 18 - Big Basin headquarters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 pm: mile 22 - Berry Creek falls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 pm: mile 28 - Waddell beach&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, a big shoutout to &lt;a href=&#34;http://redwoodhikes.com&#34;&gt;redwoodhikes.com&lt;/a&gt; that was instrumental in providing detailed maps and elevation gain/loss for this trip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;transportation&#34;&gt;Transportation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to take a ride-share to the starting location and get picked up by our friend at the end, but since there was no reception in Big Basin, we planned to check-in with him around mile 18 using a payphone at headquarters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;supplies-and-food&#34;&gt;Supplies and food&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we planned to be about 14 hours on the trail, I wanted to be more prepared in case we got stuck in the wilderness because of injury or fatigue. Therefore, I packed our backpacking first aid kit, multiple layers, headlamps, emergency blankets, and water filter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;execution&#34;&gt;Execution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a strange ride with our Lyft driver&amp;ndash;I think he was surprised to pick up two hikers so early in the morning&amp;ndash;we started around 6am. We watched the world wake up around us as we hiked the Saratoga Gap trail, and we were ahead of schedule when we reached Waterman Gap at 10am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we lost our time advantage by China Grade crossing because of the few miles of steep incline. The trail to the headquarters was a welcome change, and we were able to quickly move downhill, reaching headquarters by 2:30pm. With the extra thirty minutes, we checked in with our friend, rested and took care of blisters, and drank an energy drink, and by 3pm we were back on the trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miles 18 to 22 were by far the worst miles. Until then, I was in high spirits, excited by what I had already accomplished, but I think either my body had run out of endorphins, my perception of distance was warped, or I was suffering from inertia after resting. Regardless, those 4 miles felt like the longest of the entire trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother to stop at the waterfalls as we were quite exhausted and ready to be done with the hike so we continued drudging towards Waddell beach. I started to get stiff towards the end of the hike because I had stopped my stretching regime at every fourth mile. We got to the beach around 7:30pm, just in time to see the sunset and take our victory photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&#39;center&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;https://melinanina.github.io/images/skyline_1.jpg&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 13 and a half hours, we had just hiked 28 miles, and even with 54,000 steps, Gene still did not win the steps competition.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/d/embed?mid=1O7FuJH110Z781ZNqo-dX_WXJKoI&amp;ll=37.169677449489754%2C-122.1879525&amp;z=11&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;480&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ibex Dunes, Death Valley</title>
      <link>https://melinanina.github.io/2016/01/ibex-dunes-death-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melinanina.github.io/2016/01/ibex-dunes-death-valley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the southeastern corner of Death Valley, hidden behind the Saddle Peak Hills, there’s a small range of rolling sand dunes shaped by the strong winds called the Ibex Dunes. They reach a height of approximately 600 feet, and contrasted against sharp dry peaks off the Saddle Hills, they are quite a sight. Gene and I decided to spend New Year’s away from the parties and in solitude of this great desert in Death Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On December 30th, we loaded up the car and drove down to Death Valley. As it took a while to get there, we spent the night at Panamint Springs campground; we didn’t have reservations, and it cost us around 10 bucks. The next morning we got a free permit at Furnace Wells Visitor Center although it seemed from talking to the rangers that it was not necessary to register with the park. We loaded back into the car, drove another 40 miles, and parked our car at its final destination: off a dirt road approximately 15 miles south of Shoshone near a small electrical substation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first day out we hiked to Ibex Springs,an abandoned ghost town, and spent New Year’s eve fighting the bitter cold. The wind came from all directions and tugged on our clothes as if inviting us to flutter away with it, and it was just too cold to enjoy any stargazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://melinanina.github.io/images/ibex_dunes_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we filled up water at the spring and continued south towards Ibex Dunes. This trail was gradual downhill (about 500 feet elevation lost) with a section of deep sand. We trekked off the road towards the dunes to enjoy lunch and a break under the sandy backdrop. The sun was out and the wind had stopped so the weather was perfect. We reached Saratoga Springs in the afternoon, and the area was teeming with visitors arriving with 4x4 dune buggies. By sunset, though, we were in solitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://melinanina.github.io/images/ibex_dunes_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two interesting things we learned about the springs:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;turns out the springs doesn’t allow overnight camping, but since the ranger never said anything about our plans, we decided to stay there any way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;contrary to its name, the water at the springs was not drinkable; after some online research, I think our “tea” was salty because of borax contamination. Should I go to a doctor?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://melinanina.github.io/images/ibex_dunes_3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final morning we packed up our stuff, said goodbye to this beautiful landscape, and grudgingly hiked back to the car as we were not looking forward to our long drive home. A perfect way to start 2016!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/embed?mid=1ziXWKkmLcdeb4MOQmArESPOi5xA&amp;ll=35.722754377655086%2C-116.37654305000001&amp;z=11&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;480&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baja California, Mexico</title>
      <link>https://melinanina.github.io/2015/02/baja-california-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melinanina.github.io/2015/02/baja-california-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vityugov.com/post/bahia-de-los-angeles/&#34;&gt;Gene&lt;/a&gt; and I decided to drive down highway 1 from northern California to the middle of Baja California in early January, and in 8 days, we covered about 2000 miles (3200 kilometers). As we traveled further south from the border, the size of and proximity between towns both decreased, and gas stations, ATMs, and general amenities became few and far between. Highway 1 did not offer much in terms of tourist attractions, but the landscape offset any disappointments and was absolutely stunning: red soil, blue sky, dark green cacti sprinkled across the terrain with the occasional grey rocky mountains obscuring distant views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://melinanina.github.io/images/baja_california_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Stunning desert landscape&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our destination was a small, quiet fisherman village called Bahía de los Ángeles on the eastern side of Baja California. The bay is surrounded by islands, which makes it seem more like a lake than part of a sea. The location is great for kayaking, but due to the strong day winds, we were prevented from going out onto the water. Therefore, we enjoyed the wildlife from the shore, and we saw plenty of dolphins, sea lions, and marine birds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://melinanina.github.io/images/baja_california_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Beach view&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way home to California, we visited the Cataviña cave paintings, which are a short walk off highway 1. The paintings are interesting, but the views of the landscape really make the detour worthwhile. La Bufadora in Ensenada was underwhelming, and, thankfully, we missed the hordes of tourists and pestersome vendors by arriving before 8 am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The map below highlights our route and places to visit, dine, and stay. As a note for other tourists headed across the border, the location to pick-up the tourist visa in Mexico is in the &amp;ldquo;to declare&amp;rdquo; office as soon as crossing the border (on the right); there are few signs so ask around.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/d/embed?mid=zElkIPCwp184.kvixKYZpV-7E&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;480&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aerobatic Experience</title>
      <link>https://melinanina.github.io/2013/01/aerobatic-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melinanina.github.io/2013/01/aerobatic-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first arrived, the instructor fitted me in a jumper and explained the basics of my parachute. If I wasn&amp;rsquo;t already nervous, his causal instructions of, &amp;ldquo;Oh, it’s easy. Just climb out of the plane and throw yourself over&amp;rdquo; left me wondering, What the heck am I doing here?! I guess my nervous laugh showed my fear because as we discussed the lesson plan, he limited my instruction to the basics (&amp;ldquo;The advanced maneuvers come later with time.&amp;rdquo;)
The plane, an Extra 300L, is a super lightweight aerobatic plane (1500 lbs / 680 kg with a 300 horsepower engine), and takeoff was nearly instant. Once up in the air, he allowed me fly around, and I was amazed how sensitive the controls are. Light touches move the plane left, right, up, and down. About 7 minutes into the flight, I experienced audio loss in my headset, and there is &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=7m20s&#34;&gt;a few minutes of embarrassing footage of me spacing out and the instructor talking to himself&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I fixed the issue, we worked our way up to a cruising altitude of 4000 feet. He guided me through some of the basic maneuvers (&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=15m00s&#34;&gt;aileron roll and loop&lt;/a&gt;), and then I repeated on my own. Easy! Perhaps because I ride aggressive roller coasters frequently, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel any &amp;ldquo;butterflies&amp;rdquo; in my stomach although that didn’t save me from experiencing four times the force of gravity on the loop. I find my face all too hilarious at the bottom!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the instructor saw that &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=20m&#34;&gt;I was enjoying myself maybe too much&lt;/a&gt;, he kicked it up a notch and did more intense maneuvers. I was surprised how easy it is to get disoriented since the best point of reference, the horizon, is not always visible and the angle of flight to the sky or ground is not always apparent. &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=20m30s&#34;&gt;The Lomcevak made me dizzy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=27m15s&#34;&gt;the last trick, the tail spin, made me queasy&lt;/a&gt;. No matter, by then, it was time to land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aerobatic flights don&amp;rsquo;t last too long because the maneuvers are extremely physically and mentally tiring; I felt like I had backpacked all weekend while working through an intense math theory exam. My exhaustion and adrenaline crash hit me hard around the second hour of my drive home, and only the heaviest of 70&amp;rsquo;s and 80&amp;rsquo;s metal kept me going. The queasy feeling also settled deep in my stomach and didn’t pass until a few hours later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course as soon as I arrived home, I had to watch my video and laugh through my &amp;ldquo;Awesome!&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Woo!&amp;rdquo; remarks. Watching the video intensified the queasiness in my stomach although I had done these tricks hours earlier with no issue! Overall, though, the experience was fantastic and would highly recommend it to adventurous and interested parties. I will definitely go back! I guess I&amp;rsquo;m twisted as my instructor would say! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;List of maneuvers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=12m30s&#34;&gt;Aileron roll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=15m&#34;&gt;Loop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=16m50s&#34;&gt;Half Cuban Eight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=17m20s&#34;&gt;Immelmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=18m30s&#34;&gt;Inverted Flying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=19m20s&#34;&gt;Hammerhead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=20m30s&#34;&gt;Lomcevak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=22m&#34;&gt;Flat spin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=23m50s&#34;&gt;Chinese Loop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=25m20s&#34;&gt;Double aileron roll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/OOwIGC2bPBo?t=27m15s&#34;&gt;Tailspin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>